

Contact



1215 Belhaven Road Cary, North Carolina 27513



mickdbarnette@gmail.com



(919) 538-3699



</l>nicholasbarnette.com

Design

Figma

Illustrator

Photoshop

Development

HTML5

CSS3 / LESS / SASS

JavaScript

React / React Native

Angular

Python

MySQL/SQLite

Miscellaneous

Github / Git

Microsoft Office Suite

Windows / Mac OS X / Unix

Gradle

Gerrit

Nicholas Barnette

Front-end Developer

Profile

I am a front-end software developer with 2+ years of experience developing responsive websites and mobile applications. My passions for learning new technologies and creating visually appealing and functionally sound experiences for users allows me to push my work to the next level.

Experience

Surin Restaurant Group

July 2019 - Present

Part Time Technical Consultant

I partner with the company to develop a marketing and branding strategy with the goal of increasing searchability and to drive customers to the business. I deploy technologies to increase the efficiency of both business and customer processes. These technologies include moving payroll and POS software to the cloud, implementing online ordering, and designing and developing a mobile ordering application.

SAS Institute

June 2019 - Present

Associate Software Developer

I work with mutliple product teams to help build user interfaces that are consistent with company branding. As part of this work, I maintain a library of over one hundred common controls. This work requires me to ensure visual consistency between all major browsers as well as matching the desired user experience and visual design. I refactor large amounts of code to make it more legible and reusable.

SAS Institute

May 2016 - June 2019

Year-round Technical Intern

I implemented four custom themes across the library of over one hundred common components. I developed new features, fixed hundreds of visual bugs and helped decrease our team's overall code footprint. I also updated a smaller application's user interface to make it consistent with other newer products.

VINCI LLC.

October 2015 - June 2019

Full Stack Developer

I lead technology development for a student run startup. I designed the database, developed the RESTful server interface, and implemented the front-end web application. I interfaced with many open APIs, such as Facebook Login and Google Maps. I also developed an iOS and Android mobile application utilizing the React Native framework. Notable functionality included a real time user-to-user private messaging system using web socket technology, a social media-like feed, and safe and secure account creation and management.

Education

The University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill